VLADIK KHONONOV

SOFTWARE ARCHITECT, SPEAKER, BLOGGER, MENTOR

vladik@khononov.com +972-50-765-7534 @vladikk

Profile

I'm a software engineer with nearly 20 years of industry experience. During the years I worked for companies large and small, in roles ranging from Software Engineer to Chief Architect.

When away from work, I maintain an active media career as public speaker and blogger. I am speaking and writing on topics such as Microservices, Domain-Driven Design, and more. Alongside the media work, I have a keen professional interest in Distributed Systems, Software Architecture, and Software Design in general.

In the remaining time, I read lots of books, fly R/C aircrafts, and help animals in trouble.

Skills

Software Architecture and Design

Domain-Driven Design, Microservices, CQRS, Event Sourcing, Distributed Systems Design, Event-Driven Architecture, SOA

Cloud Computing

Amazon Web Services, Digital Ocean

Platforms and Programming Languages

.NET & .NET Core (C# & F#), Python, NodeJS (JavaScript, CoffeeScript, TypeScript), Swift

Databases

PostgreSQL, DynamoDB, MSSQL, Redis, MongoDB, Redshift

Development Methodologies

Test-Driven Development, Behavior-Driven Development

Blog

<u>vladikk.com</u> - my blog on software architecture and other related topics

Education

The Open University of Israel

Dual Major, Management and Computer Sciences, 2011 (with distinction)

Experience

Internovus - Chief Architect (2011-Present)

Internovus is a large scale online advertising and marketing company. As the first employee of the company I am in charge of both strategic and tactical software design and architecture.

At Internovus we've embraced AWS Cloud and Domain-Driven Design from the company's day one. We also employed state of the art technologies and architectural styles, such as Microservices, Serverless Computing, Event Sourcing, CQRS, Event-Driven Architecture, polyglot persistence, machine learning, and others.

In addition to my engineering duties, I built and managed international RND teams, mentored junior software developers and architects, and I'm in charge of research and technical guidance for RND teams.

At Internovus we always strove to deploy quality software, in aggressive times to market, keep the costs down, and all of this despite having very limited RND teams.

Invesus Group - Chief Architect (2017-Present)

In 2017 Internovus was merged with Invesus, and I was promoted to the Chief Architect position of the Invesus group (Internovus, Naxex). In addition to my duties at Internovus, at Invesus I'm in charge of mentoring and helping teams to migrate legacy codebases into a Microservices and cloud based solutions (AWS).

Malam Team - Senior Software Engineer (2005-2011)

Right after I demobilized from the army, I started working as a junior software engineer for one of Israel's largest outsourcing companies - Malam. I worked on numerous strategic projects for MSN, Cellcom, Coca Cola, Keshet, and other companies.

Israel Air Force - Software and IT Engineer (2001-2005)

During my army service I served as an IT manager for the Human Resources department. I was in charge of building and maintaining information management systems (Magic, MS Access), administrating databases, and supporting the department's hardware.

During the service I was honored as an *outstanding* soldier.

Beit Tochna Ve Makhshev - Web Developer (2000-2001)

During my high school years I worked as a web developer for a small chain of computer stores.

I was in charge of building websites for local shops and small businesses.

Recent Personal Projects

Domain-Driven Design

I always had a strong interest in Domain-Driven Design. For the last few years I've researched the "ins" and "outs" of this methodology, and other related patterns and practices. I posted several blogs on this subject:

Tackling Complexity in the Heart of DDD

Tackling Complexity in CQRS

Bounded Contexts are NOT Microservices

Revisiting the Basics of Domain-Driven Design

Design Heuristics for Service Boundaries

Since the Microservices trend broke out, I've been researching heuristics for designing service boundaries. I spoke about my finding at the <u>"DDD"</u> <u>eXchange 2018" conference</u>, and posted several blogs:

Tackling Complexity in Microservices

Bounded Contexts are NOT Microservices

7 Years of Domain-Driven Design (Book)

I'm writing a book, based on my talk "7 Years of Domain-Driven Design". The talk had a huge success at numerous conferences worldwide, and in the book I'll share much more details, will be able to dive deeper into technical concerns, provide code samples, and share all the information I accumulated, but had to cut from the presentation due to timing concerns.

Public Speaking

Bounded Contexts, Microservices, and Everything in Between (DDDx)

7 Years of Domain-Driven Design (Code Europe)

Full speaking profile

Publications Devops: Exploring the Value of Microblogging, Cutter IT, Jan 2012

Human Languages English - Fluent

Hebrew - Fluent

Russian - Mother tongue